# Elijah Walker

elijahwalk.r@gmail.com | linkedIn | Portfolio | GitHub | Toronto, ON

# Web Developer profile

Front-End Developer with 5+ years' experience in sociology and public policy. Through Managing 40+ client caseloads and interacting with many different informational systems I was able to work under pressure producing quality results, while fostering others' alignments behind a vision. I love and have played football competitively for over 15+ years and carry my admiration for team environments into tech. Utilizing my soft skills and attention to detail, I have a passion for bringing ideas to life through smooth, accessible, and responsive web apps.

#### **Tech Skills**

- HTML5, CSS3, SCSS
- JavaScript, jQuery
- Responsive Design, Web accessibility
- React
- RESTful APIs, Firebase
- Version control & collaboration using Git and GitHub
- Project scope management
- Paired Programming

#### Transferable Skills

Attention to Detail
Resilience

Problem Solving Interpersonal Skills

# **Education & Training**

# Juno College of Technology

Web Development, Feb 2022 – April 2022 Accelerated JavaScript, May 2022 – June 2022 Immersive Web Development, June 2022 – Sep 2022

# **University of Guelph**

Bachelor of Sociology, 2015 – 2019 Student Academic Mentor, 2018 – 2019 Leadership 360 Academy, 2017 – 2019

#### University of Guelph | 2015 – 2019

Certificate of Public Policy and Administration

Mental Health Commission of Canada | 2021

Mental Health First Aid

#### **Work Experience**

#### Stepping Stone | Housing Focused Outreach & Support Worker | September 2019 – June 2022

- Assessed 40+ clients' needs, advocated, identified, and facilitated the obtaining of affordable housing and assisted with referrals to social, medical and substance abuse disorder resources.
- Connected individuals to long-term housing stability programs through rapport building and collaboration with community stakeholders such as Guelph-Wellington's Coordinated Entry System, Ontario Disability Support Program, OW, City of Guelph By-Law, Medical Services and more
- Received 2 promotions from a front-line role to a leadership role in less than 12 months through active
  engagement on client's case managing planning resulting in becoming hired into a new position

### Wyndham House | Program Housing Staff | February 2018 - September 2019

- Supported vulnerable youth with concurrent disorders through facilitating client's access to medication, crisis intervention support and fostering a positive and growth environment
- Assessed, screened, and documented client's intakes and provided referrals to community supports as needed through effective knowledge on the Homelessness Individuals and Families Informational System

# **Projects**

# Project Name (Skills: , , ,) | GitHub link

-explanation that will be tailored based on company job posting

# Project Name (Skills: , , ,) | GitHub link

-explanation that will be tailored based on company job pos